Previously on Transformers Prime...
在上一集中
Download of the Iacon database may have been incomplete,
尽管下载到的铁堡数据不完整
but we now possess four sets of coordinates decoded by the ship.
但我们已经拥有了战舰所破译的四个坐标
If we are to have any hope of recovering the Iacon relics before the Decepticons do
如果我们想赶在霸天虎之前 得到铁堡的遗物
we must divide our resources.
我们就必须分头行动
Dispatching multiple squadrons will enable us to pursue all four coordinates simultaneously.
派出多支小队 同时前往这四个地点
I will embark for the Antarctica.
我将前往南极
As for you, old friend,
至于你 我的老朋友
I would prefer that you have company on your mission.
我想让一个人陪同你执行任务
You can't be serious.
你不是认真的吧！
Wheeljack is insubordinate, a ruffian!
千斤顶桀骜不驯 粗俗无礼！
Wheeljack is a highly capable warrior.
千斤顶是个强大的战士
You would be wise to welcome the temporary alliance.
由他暂时陪同对你有好处
The boss thought you needed backup, huh?
头儿认为你需要支援 嗯？
If you must know
如果你一定要知道
Optimus feels strongly that you require supervision.
擎天柱强烈认为你需要监督！
I'll be sure to be on my best behavior, Doc.
我会好好表现的 大夫
Please, don't call me "Doc".
请不要叫我“大夫”！
Whatever you say... sunshine.
随便你怎么说 阳光老男孩
En...
呃…
So, all of team Prime's busy chasing down these four Iacon relics?
这么说 领袖卫队都去忙着寻找四个铁堡遗物了？
The four which are currently in play.
这是目前所知的四个
There's more?
还有更多？
Megatron maintains possession of the entire Iacon database.
威震天拥有整个铁堡数据库
We have yet to learn how many more relics
我们需要查出其中还包含多少遗物
or Decepticon weapons of mass destruction it contains.
或是霸天虎的大规模杀伤性武器
No worries, Doc. I've got your back.
别担心 大夫 我来罩着你！
My name is not "Doc"!
哦 我的名字不是“大夫”
And I do not require anyone watching my back!
而且我也不需要任何人来帮忙！
I proved my metal during the war for Cybertron.
在塞博特恩之战中我已经证实了自己的能力
Then I'm lucky you're along for the ride, champ.
那我很荣幸能有你同行 战神
'Cause we got a bogie on our tail.
看来我们带了个尾巴
Soundwave!
声波！
Megatron's communications chief?
威震天的通讯官？
He must be tracking the same coordinates.
他一定也在追踪这个遗物
You might want to grab on to something.
你最好抓紧扶手！
Are you trying to send us to the scrap yard?
你是想把咱们都送进废料场吗？
What's that?
那是什么？
Soundwave's surveillance drone, Laserbeak.
声波的放哨喽罗 激光鸟！
Wheeljack, maintain pursuit!
千斤顶 继续追击！
Soundwave is merely using the drone to distract us.
声波只是用它来转移我们的注意力！
I welcome a good distraction.
我喜欢这个干扰
The hunter becomes the hunted.
猎人变成猎物了
This is no time to be hot-dogging.
没时间进行追捕游戏了！
He is gone. Now, we can go find Soundwave.
他跑了 现在我们要去找到声波…哇噢！
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
Wheeljack? Wheeljaaack!
千斤顶？千――斤――顶――！
Took up that, Con!
吃得消吗 虎子？
You did it!
你打中了！
Right thruster's fried.
啊…右侧推进器烧毁了！
If you had pursuit Soundwave as I instructed...
如果你听我的去追声波…
His little birdie would still be pecking at our tailpipes.
他的小鸟还是会来啄我们的排气管！
Well, we need to resume our search for the relic immediately.
好吧 我们需要立刻继续追踪遗物！
Soundwave may already have reached it.
声波没准儿已经找到它了！
The Jackhammer is not going anywhere.
钻击号飞不了啦
If you wanna catch that Con,
要想追上那个虎子
we need to roll.
我们得靠轮子！
Make up your mind.
那快决定啊！
Are we walking or are we driving?
是步行还是开过去？
Wheeljack, keep your distance.
千斤顶 注意保持距离！
Laserbeak is the eyes and ears of Soundwave.
激光鸟是声波的耳目！
Not anymore, it isn't.
它现在什么也不是了！
Operating system appears functional but offline.
操作系统仍然完好 但停机了
However the crash clearly damaged its optic and audio receptors.
看来撞击损坏了它的光学和音频接收器
Guess someone's gonna need a new snitch.
看来有人得换侦察兵了！
A minor victory and not the one we're here to achieve.
小胜一局 这不是我们此行的目的
Hang on there, Doc.
在这等一会儿 大夫
Oh!
啊！
Situation's right for an old wrecker trick.
这形势正适合玩一个老把戏
I am... not sure I follow.
我…我不太明白
Sooner or later Soundwave's gonna come looking for his pet.
声波早晚会寻回他的宠物
We let them reunite and return to base
我们可以让他们重逢 回到基地
packing a light grenade.
同时带去一个手雷！
The first time 'Wave reaches inside,
等到声波去摸里面
it rips the bang and kaboom!
他就会碰触到机关 然后 卡――砰！
Why plant a mere insanitary device?
与其植入一个小小的燃烧弹
When we could plant a more devastating bomb.
何不植入一个更具毁灭性的炸弹呢？
A virus.
一个病毒！
Engineered to pass from Laserbeak to Soundwave.
通过激光鸟来感染声波
Then directly into the Decepticon warship's mainframe,
然后 直接侵入霸天虎战舰的主机
where it will transmit the content of the entire Iacon database to us.
通过它将整个铁堡数据库传送给我们
Sounds complicated. Thought we were in a hurry.
听上去挺复杂 咱们不是在赶时间吗？
Optimus would agree.
擎天柱会认同的
Risking the loss of one relic to gain the rest is a worthwhile gamble.
赌上一个遗物 换取其余所有的遗物 值得一搏
You really have a chance to pull off that kind of programming?
你真的有能力编好这样的程序？
Not alone. I will require backup.
嗯…我一个人不行 还需要个帮手
Raphael. We have a situation.
拉斐尔 我们这里有情况
If you could write a source code for the virus,
如果你能编写一段病毒源代码
my scanner will translate it to Cybertronian script as it uploads.
我的扫描仪可以 在上传过程中将它转译为塞博特恩代码
I can do it.
我能行！
but if you wanna keep the virus hidden from the 'Cons
但如果我们想让病毒骗过虎子
we'll need a decoy, you know,
我们需要一个诱饵 你知道的
like a second virus.
比如伪装病毒
Or something less complicated.
可以更简单一点
A decoy as in... we wanted them to find it
诱饵的意思是 我们希望被他们发现
but it doesn't blow?
但又不会爆炸？
Correct.
正确
Seems like a waste of a perfectly good grenade.
可惜了一颗上好的手雷
Wait a minute, a grenade inside of Laserbeak inside of Soundwave.
等等 手雷在激光鸟体内 激光鸟又在声波体内？
Like a "turducken".
真像火鸭鸡！
I'm sorry?
什么？
It's a turkey stuffed with a duck, stuffed with...
一个火鸡里填上鸭子 鸭子里填上…
nevermind.
…啊 算了！
And where are you off to?
你要去哪儿？
To buy you some time, and who knows,
为你争取些时间 然后 说不定
maybe to pick up a relic.
还能捡个遗物回来
You dropped something.
你东西掉了
This should be fun.
要玩点刺激的了
Here I go again... shattering expectations.
我的拿手戏 不让人如愿
Rafael, I jacked in the Laserbeak's supplying transmitter.
拉斐尔 我接入了激光鸟的上行传输器
When you're ready I will bring its operating system back online and order it to receive the transfer.
你准备好后 我会启动它的操作系统以接收数据
Any last words?
有什么遗言吗？
Right, silent type.
对哦 闷骚型的
Ratchet, the virus is coded. Commencing upload.
救护车 病毒编写完成 开始上传
Rafael, what is our progress?
拉斐尔 我们的进展如何？
50 percent.
50%
Doc.
呃 大夫？
Wheeljack, I told you not to call me that!
千斤顶 我告诉过你别那样叫我！
I'm sorry.
对不起
What's wrong, where are you?
怎么了？你在哪儿？
Think you got maybe... two minutes.
我估计你还有两分钟
Or less.
也许更少
Wheeljack, what is your condition? Wheeljack!
千斤顶你的情况如何？千斤顶？
Rafael?
拉斐尔？
We're almost there.
马上就好！
Done.
完成！
Scrap!
糟了！
Soundwave has taken the bait. Wheeljack?
声波上钩了 千斤顶？
Scrap.
见鬼！
The resonance blaster!
啊 共振炮！
Crafted by Decepticon scientist for maximum sonic devastation.
霸天虎科学家设计的最为强大的音波毁灭武器
Soundwave, you have performed admirably
声波 你表现得很好
unlike Dreadwing here
不像骇翼
who somehow managed to loose the APEX armor to Starscream.
竟然将精锐护甲送到了红蜘蛛手上！
However, two more decrypted coordinates remain in play.
不过还有两组坐标
And I have every confidence that Knockout and I...
我很信任击倒 并且我…
Can you believe what the autobots did to me?!
你们能想象到汽车人对我做了什么吗？！
Did you retrieve the relic?
你找回遗物了吗？！
No, master.
没有 主人
Then I suggest you convince me of your continuing usefulness
那么我建议你现在修好激光鸟
by examining Laserbeak, Doctor.
以向我证明你仍有利用价值 医生
Wheeljack!
千斤顶！
Just resting my optics.
啊 我只是休息下光学镜
And my audio receptors.
唔 和音频接收器
What is it?
怎么了？
An obstruction of some sort.
有某种阻塞物
Grenade!
手雷！
Ah, that is clever. Knockout,
啊 真聪明 击倒
prepare to properly dispose of the obstruction.
准备好去处理下这个“阻塞物”
Soundwave, if we're to maintain any advantage over the Autobots,
声波 如果我们想保持对汽车人的优势…
decoding the remainder of the Iacon database must remain your top priority.
…破译剩余的铁堡数据仍是你的首要任务！
Rafael, send the groundbridge.
拉斐尔 打开环陆桥
I still advice that you return to base.
我还是建议你回到基地
You require a thorough examination.
你需要全面的检查
The only thing I require right now is some hole sealant.
我现在需要的是船体密封剂
Trust me, the Jackhammer here is in more need of repair than me.
相信我 钻击号比我更需要修理
Listen, Wheeljack. I want to...
听着 千斤顶 我只是想…
Thank you... for your backup.
谢谢你的…支援
Yep.
好的
See you around, Ratchet.
注意 回见 救护车
Ratchet, come here!
救护车 到这边来！
The Iacon database?
铁堡数据库？
It's downloading to our mainframe!
它下载到我们的主机上来了！
Rafael, you are a genius.
哈哈哈！拉斐尔你真是个天才！
Oh, believe me,
哦 相信我
Soundwave will provide the coordinates to the remaining relics.
声波会破译剩余遗物的坐标的
Yes, we are fortunate to have him on our side, lord Megatron.
是的 拥有他是我们的福气 威震天陛下
And see about repairing his cracked visor, will you?
那么你会修复他破损的面甲 不是吗？
Ummm...
哼…
Bulkhead is coming through, Agent Fowler.
隔板回来了 福勒探员
I can't wait to share the news.
我等不及要分享这个消息了！
No!
不…！